Betsy Perkins Hill

1002 Timber Lane Wilmette, IL 60091 betsyhill@comcast.net 847-853-0518 (H) 847-853-0519 (F) 847-644-0093 (C)

CAREER SUMMARY

Marketing and business development executive with multi-functional experience emphasizing creative solutions to complex business issues in unstructured settings, managing products and services from concept to profitability. Diverse domestic and international experience in marketing, product/business management and commercialization, integrated communications, investor relations, government and regulatory affairs and strategic planning.

EXPERIENCE AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS

LEARNING ENHANCEMENT CORPORATION, Chicago, IL

2005 to Present

Developer of learning programs that merge neuroscience and video-game technology.

President & Chief Operating Officer

- Managed the launch of BrainWare Safari in multiple channels: Consumer, Education and Health Care and Corporate.
- Directed the establishment of the value proposition through research, partnerships, endorsements.
- Manage the establishment and integration of operational systems and processes to support company growth on an ongoing basis.
- Manage implementation of all strategic partnerships and marketing programs.
- Managed the company to cash-flow breakeven through the economic downturn.

LAKE FOREST GRADUATE SCHOOL OF MANAGEMENT, Lake Forest, IL 2003 to Present Independent, not-for-profit business management education.

Business Management Professor

 Teach core Strategic Thinking course, focusing on business strategy, case analysis, and the general manager's perspective.

MARKETING PRO TEMPORE, Wilmette, IL

2003 to 2006

Temporary or part-time marketing resource, strategy consultant.

President

Sample projects and services:

- Consulted on business strategy and developed an initial business plan for a start-up firm managing the development and manufacture of private and controlled label beverage products for national and regional retailers.
- Led the development efforts for a new product for a successful privately held energy information services company.
- Develop and execute marketing and growth strategy for a small consulting firm serving the
 retail and consumer packaged goods industries. Conducted customer research which led to
 redefining and stronger differentiation of the firm's services. Revamped web and collateral.
- Assessed the role a new technology could play in enhancing value and differentiating the services of a national provider of home and industrial cleaning services.

Betsy Perkins Hill Page 2

THE VIALINK COMPANY, Dallas, Texas

2000 to 2003

A prematurely public company, viaLink (now owned by Prescient Technologies) was the leading provider of data synchronization and advanced e-commerce services to the retail supply chain.

Director, Marketing

Provided leadership in the transition from a technology-driven company to a market- and customer-driven culture. Defined the company's service offerings and positioning in a complex and rapidly evolving market through direct responsibility for the company's marketing, public relations and investor relations functions.

- Conceived and executed innovative marketing programs for the company's retailer-centric community development (supplier recruitment) efforts.
- Introduced the company's suite of advanced commerce services, including its industry-leading scan based trading service. The company's advanced commerce services grew to represent 60% of revenues in three years.
- Developed and implemented low-cost communications vehicles, including online advertising, electronic newsletters and email campaigns that generated strong response and actionable leads.
- Authored a series of well-regarded white papers on salient industry issues and the role of the company's services in addressing them.
- Provided strategic marketing direction for business planning, service definition and development, customer project delivery and sales.

ILLINOVA ENERGY PARTNERS, Oak Brook, Illinois

1996 to 2000

A \$750 million subsidiary of Illinova Corporation (a \$7 billion company, subsequently acquired by Dynegy, Inc.) which markets energy and energy-related services to commercial and industrial customers. Illinova Energy Partners was the deregulated energy services affiliate of Illinois Power (electric and gas utility).

Managing Director, Energy Information Services / Product and Services Marketing Led the development and successful commercialization of energy information products and services, becoming the market leader. Managed all facets of product/service development and marketing for this start-up energy services company.

- Developed a full line of energy information products and services, both software and outsourced services, to address the needs of large and small multi-site organizations, including some of the country's leading retail and manufacturing organizations.
- Accountable for EIS Business profitability, managing software development, project implementation and sales and marketing teams. Managed award-winning marketing campaign to firmly establish the product line as the industry leader.
- Negotiated exclusive marketing rights with UK leader of outsourced energy information management, creating the first-ever international energy management capability.
- Established new product and service screening and development processes and led group of product managers to enhance product line profitability and to build Illinova's credibility outside the utility's regulated territory.
- Provided marketing consulting internally and to strategic wholesale electricity customers regarding the transition to a competitive market and customer retention.

Betsy Perkins Hill Page 3

THE NUTRASWEET COMPANY, Deerfield, Illinois

1982 to 1996

A \$700 million subsidiary of Monsanto Company that manufactures and markets food ingredients and tabletop sweeteners.

Director, Food Systems Group (1993-1996)

P&L responsibility for the company's fat substitute, Simplesse[®], attaining profitability for the first time in the product's history. Crystallized a vision and led expeditionary marketing effort leveraging the company' technical abilities in lower fat foods to ingredient systems and marketable finished formulations and product concepts.

- Achieved sales volume growth of 100% in the first year, with ongoing annual double-digit increases, through pricing, focused customer technical support, the introduction of baking formulations and improved sales support and incentives.
- Introduced Crème Culinaire[™] butter and cream replacer for chefs into the foodservice market. Conducted successful test market demonstrating business potential in the range of \$10-40 million for the product. Negotiated license agreement with division of Nestle enabling a national product launch.
- Developed customized low-fat snack food items launched by national distributed manufacturers or baked goods, including product attributes, contract manufacturing capacity, package design, cost-pricing, marketing materials and partnerships.
- Served on Monsanto task for developing growth initiatives; three proposals to advance the corporation's foods strategies were funded.

Director, Communications, Government Affairs and Regulatory Policy (1985-1993)Directed the US government affairs program, regulatory policy development, regulatory approvals in international markets and public relations support for various business areas.

- Marshaled the resources of the company, recruited and managed a network of lobbyists and consultants, and built alliances with external constituencies to respond successfully to two sets of Congressional hearings on the safety of NutraSweet[®], as well as challenges at the state and local level.
- Analyzed and responded to Food and Drug Administration regulations under the Nutrition Labeling and Education Act to protect and expand opportunities for the company's products; co-authored articles for published regulatory texts.
- Obtained regulatory approvals for NutraSweet, Simplesse and developmental products in Canada and Mexico.
- Built the NutraSweet Classic (golf tournament) program from inception to five-city series, raising \$500,000 annually for the Juvenile Diabetes Foundation.

Manager, Strategic Planning (1982-1984)

Provided analytical support and developed the first two strategic plans for the NutraSweet Group.

OFFICE OF GOVERNOR JAMES R. THOMPSON, Chicago, Illinois ILLINOIS DEPARTMENT OF PROFESSIONAL REGULATION

1977 to 1980

Assistant to Director; Coordinator of Program Development

As a member of the Governor's program staff:

- Established and staffed a blue ribbon committee to review the Department's licensing examination procedures; consulted on implementation of the recommendations.
- Directed the work of professional licensing committees to overhaul the Department's rules and regulations.
- Wrote and worked for passage of legislation to repeal regulatory laws automatically if not reenacted.
- Recommended the Governor's approval or veto of legislation.

Betsy Perkins Hill Page 4

THE NORTH SHORE COUNTRY DAY SCHOOL

1974 to 1977

Teacher of High School French, Russian and Spanish

EDUCATION

J.L. Kellogg Graduate School of Management, MBA with distinction, Beta Gamma Sigma, 1982 Northwestern University, MAT, 1975

Wellesley College, BA with honors in the major, Phi Beta Kappa, Durant Scholar, 1974

PROFESSIONAL AND CIVIC ACTIVITIES

Chicago State University, Former Chairman, Board of Trustees and Former Chair, Academic & Student Affairs Committee
The North Shore Country Day School, Former Trustee and Chair, Education Committee